<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/firstjek/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/firstjek/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-19T18:33:11+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/firstjek/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Code &amp;amp; Coffe</title><subtitle>A personal blog by a curious CSE student exploring the world of code, bugs, and tech!  This space is my learning ground where I share my experiments, silly mistakes, and everything in between.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Silly Mistake I’ll Never Forget</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/firstjek/jekyll/update/2025/04/19/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Silly Mistake I’ll Never Forget" /><published>2025-04-19T14:22:25+05:30</published><updated>2025-04-19T14:22:25+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/firstjek/jekyll/update/2025/04/19/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/firstjek/jekyll/update/2025/04/19/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every journey has its first step — and often, a stumble or two.</p>

<p>Today, I want to share something small but important from my very first experience using GitHub.</p>

<h3 id="the-mistake">The Mistake</h3>

<p>When I first uploaded my project to GitHub, I <strong>accidentally committed my entire <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">node_modules</code> folder</strong> — over 800 files!<br />
I had no idea that such folders <strong>should not be pushed to GitHub</strong>, and it made my repository look bloated and messy.</p>

<p>Honestly, it felt a little embarrassing at first — especially because this was my <strong>very first time</strong> using Git and GitHub.</p>

<h3 id="what-i-learned">What I Learned</h3>

<p>But instead of deleting everything or panicking, I took a deep breath and <strong>learned how to fix it</strong>. Here’s what I did:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I learned about <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.gitignore</code> and how to prevent unwanted files from being tracked.</li>
  <li>I cleaned my repository and made a fresh commit.</li>
  <li>I also understood that <strong>mistakes are part of learning</strong> — especially when you’re experimenting.</li>
</ul>

<p>This one small issue helped me understand Git better than any tutorial could have.</p>

<h3 id="the-best-part">The Best Part</h3>

<p>Now, I’m writing this post on my <strong>very first Jekyll site</strong>, which is hosted on GitHub Pages — and that alone feels amazing.<br />
Yes, I made mistakes, but I learned, fixed them, and kept moving forward.</p>

<p>If you’re just starting out with Git, GitHub, or Jekyll — <strong>don’t worry about messing up.</strong> Everyone does. What matters is learning from it.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading,<br />
– Saif</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every journey has its first step — and often, a stumble or two.]]></summary></entry></feed>